<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Short Stories</title>
  <subtitle>A collection of short stories built with 11ty</subtitle>
  <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/stories/" />
  <updated>2025-03-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/stories/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Luke</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Knocking on the young lady&#39;s door</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/knocking-on-the-young-ladys-door/" />
    <updated>2025-03-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/knocking-on-the-young-ladys-door/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Good morning, Mr. Broughton.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Please, Alice, I insist you call me Henry.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m afraid that would be most disrespectful of me, Mr. Broughton.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Surely not, if I am rightly confident in your response to my most recent parcel.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m afraid I haven’t had the time to read the mail.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Haven’t the time at all?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Oh even now, I am behind. The clothes must be washed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Then after.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“They must be hung.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Surely after that.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I am picking up bread from the bakery with Ni—Mr. Thatcher.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I could escort you instead.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’d hate to trouble you. Now excuse me, Mr. Broughton.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Honeyed Thank-yous</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/honeyed-thank-yous/" />
    <updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/honeyed-thank-yous/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Outside the culinary college’s entrance stood a bulletin board surrounded by students. The crowd pushed among themselves trying to see how they ranked on the midterm exam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A young man with unkempt curls quickly found his name:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. Fletcher Moore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He nodded, allowing himself a small smile, then turned and exited the crowd. A young woman with shoulder length black hair sat on a bench, her leg rapidly moving up and down. She was staring at him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He recognized her, of course. They&#39;d never spoken, but she was a standout both in and outside of class. And he had just seen her name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. Robin Smyth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She stood and walked toward him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Show me what you made.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Uh, right now?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yes.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What an odd introduction,&lt;/em&gt; he mused as they walked in silence into the college.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forty-five minutes later, she took a bite of the beef tenderloin he&#39;d prepared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Interesting. So you’d rather emphasize the other ingredients? The butter’s creaminess really comes through.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, that butter’s local. I think unique ingredients like that are worth emphasizing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She looked at him with curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few days later, Fletcher found himself walking through the college’s halls late.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only one room had a light on. Inside stood the #2 student. She was finishing a cake, clearly exhausted. Surrounding her was a mess of dirty cookware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He walked in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She looked up at him. “It won’t be ready tonight. It has to set.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I know.” He made his way to the sink and began washing a large mixing bowl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Helping you out.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You don’t have to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She sighed and began to protest, but he cut her off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You should be honored that the #1 student is offering his help as your bus boy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She smirked. “#1, for now.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If you want to back that talk, you better get back to finishing that cake.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Whatever.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They walked home together in silence. But as they began to go their separate ways, she spoke.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Sorry for making you do all the dishes.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You didn’t make me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Well, I guess. But still, sorry about that. Must not have been fun.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’d feel better if you said &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;sorry.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Oh. Well, thank you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You’re welcome.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A month later, the next exam came. And once again, students crowded around the bulletin board afterward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fletcher immediately saw two names:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. Robin Smyth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. Fletcher Moore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Damn.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He didn’t think he’d take it hard, but he felt himself shaking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No. It doesn’t matter. I did fine. She worked hard for the spot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He exited the crowd and saw her once again sitting on that same bench, staring at him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time he walked over to her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Hey, congratulations on getting first.” He smiled, then kept on walking. He could tell his eyes were betraying him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Want me to show you what I made?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He stopped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is she trying to brag?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He looked into her eyes. He didn’t see any sign of disrespect. &lt;em&gt;Is this her way of offering support?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He didn’t want to care. But, she knew he did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Thank you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that, they began practicing together in the evenings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They watched their souffles deflate together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They spent too long caramelizing onions together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They made whipped cream together — hers always overwhipped and his always underwhipped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They talked about this and that, everything and nothing as the semester went by.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, they moved their late night cooking to their own apartments. One night, the topic of pancakes came up at Fletcher’s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robin rolled her eyes. “Pancakes are such a bleh food.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Hey now, I think they’re a great comfort food.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yeah if you’re sad and alone at a McDonalds.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He laughed. “I can make a sophisticated pancake breakfast! It’s mostly about what you put on them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Okay, make me some then.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s 8 p.m. That’s not pancake time.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Really? It could be a dessert.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Pancakes truly shine as an early morning treat. Like, breakfast in bed type of thing. Asking them to fill the role of a fancy evening dessert is setting them up for failure.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He could tell she disagreed from her frown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“How about you come over tomorrow morning and I’ll make you some then.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She smiled. “Okay, does… 6 a.m. work?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He raised his eyes at her. “I’m not getting up that early, sorry.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She took a step toward him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why did my heart just skip a beat?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What if I wake you up myself?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;She can’t have meant that in the way I’m taking it, right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He stared into her eyes. Then subconsciously dropped his gaze to her lips. She had a small tense smile. Was she nervous?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Was he nervous? He certainly felt warm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He looked up. Her eyes were gazing at his own lips now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They both stood there in silence for an uncountable moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He tried to speak. His voice came out airy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What do you mean by that?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She closed the half step between them and ran her hand through his hair. And her lips were on his.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And his were on hers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then his hands were on her back, and then her front.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And soon she was on top of him in his bed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And much later they fell asleep together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robin woke to the smell of pancakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She rubbed her eyes and sat up in bed. The light from the window shone on her face. She couldn’t believe she had woken up so late. But then she thought about their late night, and decided she could in fact believe it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Downstairs she found the #2 student drizzling honey upon a fluffy pancake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His green eyes sparkled as he noticed her. He scooped a finger of honey off the plate and put it in his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“So the secret is the honey. It’s hyperlocal honey made from a single hive surrounded by maple trees. You can truly taste—”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She kissed him. And yes, she could taste the maple.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s delicious. Thank you.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What do we do with potatoes?</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/what-do-we-do-with-potatoes/" />
    <updated>2024-11-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/what-do-we-do-with-potatoes/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Twenty-one soldiers marched down a wooded trail. The man leading, Captain, led them in chant, and they responded in unison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What do we do when frying ‘em?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Slice ‘em long-ways into strips!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every few minutes they came upon a potato on the ground. Each time, Captain reached down, grabbed it, and tossed it in the closest wagon without breaking stride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What do we do after boiling ‘em?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Mash ‘em up with something blunt!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At every crossroad, Captain sent a man down each path. They took whichever path one had spotted a potato. The men’s grins grew as they eagerly marched onward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What do we do when roasting ‘em?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Pierce through their skin with a fork!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They spotted a wagon. It was full of enough potatoes that the pile sat above the sides. Their chanting and marching speed increased.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What do we do with the sprouts on ‘em?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Cut off the eyes with a knife!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They arrived at the wagon. Its front right wheel had slipped off the trail and was stuck in the mud of a gentle ravine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The captain led them around to the side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What do we do to get more of ‘em?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Bury ‘em in soil and drown ‘em!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They saw a man, wearing the same uniform as them, frantically trying to lift the wheel. Captain walked over and grabbed him by the collar. He dragged him over to the men and held him up for all to see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What do we do once we’ve caught ‘em?”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anticipation</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/anticipation/" />
    <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/anticipation/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“You may leave once you open the bottle.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She stared at the plain wine bottle, then at the gray room she was in. There was only a bed and a pail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“But I haven’t a corkscrew.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guard just grinned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She figured the whole situation must be some sort of puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guard laid down on the bed, looking at her. The smug grin remained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She ran her fingers across the walls, thinking perhaps the puzzle’s trick was with the room itself. Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She did the same with the floor. Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She even examined the bed the guard was laying on. He did not object, but he did not move. Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pail was simply a pail. Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She then had an epiphany. She picked up the wine bottle from the floor and walked over to the wall. She raised her hand up and—&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If any wine touches the floor, it doesn’t count,” said the guard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She put the bottle down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her brain cycled through the same ideas over and over. She even asked the guard if he had anything on him she could use. He had nothing but his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For hours she stared at the bottle. Then she stared at the guard, and that thick mattress underneath him. It gave her a horrible idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two guards in a surveillance room watched through a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m not kinkshaming Dave for being a masochist — but his blood ruins a lot of good mattresses.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I dunno, that sounds like kinkshaming.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A recipe for one boy</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/a-recipe-for-one-boy/" />
    <updated>2024-07-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/a-recipe-for-one-boy/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Now, squish it between your fingers.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A young girl named Poppy was preparing banana bread with her mother in their forest cottage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Poppy loved squishing the ingredients together, but it frustrated her that she couldn’t get the lumps out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Oh, the oven will take care of that, if we ask nicely.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her mother took her to the brick oven in the yard that stood roughly the same height as Poppy. The oven confused her, but she supposed magic wouldn’t make sense, and this was clearly a magic oven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her mother placed the loaves within and shut the big iron door. Then she looked over at Poppy, who nodded. The two spoke in unison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Magic oven, be so kind, yummy bread would be so divine!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While she spoke, Poppy looked through the cracks in the door as the magic oven roared to life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not once did she ever notice her mother igniting the kerosene with a lever near her foot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That evening, Poppy walked through the woods while eating her perfectly baked banana bread. She was with two boys: Lex and Anders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She liked Anders a lot. A quiet boy with glasses, his sunken eyes and crooked nose didn’t make him very popular with the other girls. But he was so considerate and never excluded her for being a girl when she wanted to play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lex was quite different. He was tall and strong, which went to his head. He always bossed people around and had a nasty habit of trying to one-up Poppy, which she thought was especially unnecessary. She found it gross that all the other girls wanted to marry a dumb boy like Lex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She had a horrible secret, though. She, despite knowing how horrible he was, recently began finding him very handsome. She wished there was a &lt;em&gt;nice&lt;/em&gt; handsome boy somewhere so she could forget about Lex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She hated how she would wish sweet Anders was that handsome boy. But when she looked at Anders, she just could not make herself like him like that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As they all walked along, she imagined squishing the two boys between her fingers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She paused.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then she frantically told the boys she had lost her favorite hair tie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lex just laughed, but Anders asked her where she had it last. She told them it was when she was cleaning the oven. But then she shook her head, saying going back to the oven again was much too scary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lex laughed at her again, but Anders immediately volunteered to search. Lex glared at him and said &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; would go search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And so the trio set out to her oven. Lex shoved Anders aside, then stooped down and entered. Anders followed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As soon as the boys went in, she slammed the door shut and pushed against it with all her weight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lex banged on the door, telling her it wasn’t funny. Anders didn’t say anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She closed her eyes tight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Magic oven, be so kind, a yummy boy would be so divine!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Applicants need not apply</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/applicants-need-not-apply/" />
    <updated>2023-12-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/applicants-need-not-apply/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In an otherwise dark room, a computer screen cast a harsh blue on a man’s face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Face identified. Please confirm the following to begin the job application:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below was his name, address, birthdate, citizen status, and physical measurements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He clicked “Continue.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please fill out your work history.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added his work history. “Continue.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The information is incorrect. Records show you worked at C8 Enterprises until May. Please try again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He accidentally selected March. He corrected it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few generic work-related questions followed. Then the screen showed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You have eaten at McDonald&#39;s four times in the last month. We take the health and healthcare costs of our employees very seriously. Are you willing to abstain from fast food while you are employed with us?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yes.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You have been sexually active with three people in the last fiscal year. We are extracting the relevant feelings from your former partners. One moment, please.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A minute passed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amy Finnegan felt the experience was “unsatisfactory.” Please explain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He remembered Amy didn’t like his non-augmented body, so he typed “Beauty is subjective” and clicked “Continue.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We highly value our brand’s physical presence. Are you willing to undergo surgery if necessary for your employment?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He clicked “Yes” then “Submit application.” He held his breath.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you! Unfortunately, we will not be considering you for this position. Best of luck elsewhere!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sighed, and clicked on another job. His face was recognized, he confirmed his personal information, and saw the familiar screen:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please fill out your work history.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A puzzling invitation</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/a-puzzling-invitation/" />
    <updated>2023-10-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/a-puzzling-invitation/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Another puzzle solved!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The video game console congratulated the young woman holding it. She laid back against the sofa in triumph.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She looked down at a young man dozing, his head on her thigh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I wish real life had more puzzles.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleepily, he nodded in agreement. She smiled, stroking his hair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The letter arrived a few days later. She recognized the book-shaped postage stamp. Every letter she received from him had it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside she found a gold-trimmed card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You are cordially invited to breakfast this Sunday. Please arrive at 10 o’clock sharp, following the instructions below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Begin at the best cafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then walk through the trees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the scent of Kennedy’s rose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To find me under your shadow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She stared at the note with excitement. A real life puzzle!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Begin at the best cafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As she laid in bed Saturday night, she was still stuck on that first line. The term “best” was so subjective. But as she fell asleep, she remembered a conversation that happened last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He had been at the stove making pancakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She handed him a cup of coffee. “You don&#39;t have to cook, ya know. We could eat out.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He took a sip. “Between your coffee and my food, this is the best cafe in town.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You&#39;re ridiculous.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He gestured towards her balcony. “Besides, I already made a reservation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And so on Sunday morning, she set forth from her apartment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then walk through the trees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once she knew where to start, that line became obvious. Leif Street began across from her apartment. She walked down it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow the scent of Kennedy’s rose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once she knew to walk down Leif Street, she knew to walk to the Kennedy running track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She found no roses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She climbed the bleachers and looked across the track. Below was an engraved compass rose. It pointed not North, but Northeast, supposedly towards Marathon, Greece, across the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Down the steps she went. Then down Layton Street, which ran Northeast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To find me under your shadow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As she walked, she kept glancing down. There, her shadow unhelpfully followed her. She frowned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She passed by a small park. A statue of Aphrodite stood in its center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She paused - half amused, half horrified. He once told her she must be the reincarnation of Aphrodite. She remembered nervously laughing as he turned red.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She reached the statue as a bell tower chimed in the distance. Exactly 10:00.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goddess cast a shadow down an alley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turning the corner, she came upon a quaint cafe. There, he sat at a table for two.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A waiter approached with drinks. “A cappuccino with extra foam.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She sat down. “That’s me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The waiter placed the drinks down and left. They took their first sips as the morning sun came into view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He grinned, basking in his ever-so-clever puzzle. “I heard this is the second best cafe in town.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Likewise, she was basking in her ever-so-clever solution. “A worthy reward.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each basked in the presence of their person.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It&#39;s cold</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/its-cold/" />
    <updated>2023-08-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/its-cold/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“It’s cold.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The young man puts on his gloves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He steps through the year’s first snowfall to a wheelbarrow. He loads a pile of logs tucked under his cottage’s eaves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He puts the logs in the truck bed. Their weight will add traction. He knows snowy roads are dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He gets inside the cabin he always expects to be warmer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s cold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive is long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A sign asks everyone to drive safely - in memory of a woman he doesn&#39;t know. He’s the only one driving today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blizzard comes suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He turns on the windshield wiper. Whipping into the ice, it stops, then snaps. The snow builds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He misses a curve. The truck careens off the road, then stops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He breathes. And he breathes and he breathes and thinks about how he’s still breathing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His truck is half-buried in a snowdrift. It isn’t starting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s cold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He calls the emergency line. They say they can’t reach him until the blizzard ends tomorrow morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has an old sleeping bag tucked away. He curls up in the front seat and waits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time moves slower when it’s cold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s cold.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He turns his head, confused why he’s hearing his thoughts aloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His eyes meet those of a passenger: a young woman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He pauses, then nods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s cold.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She pauses, then introduces herself, asking if he minds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He shakes his head, then realizes he’s seen her name. He saw it on a sign.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She recognizes the recognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She says she was also stuck in a blizzard. They didn’t rescue her in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cold killed her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He doesn’t know what to say. She tells him he doesn’t need to say anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another pause.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She asks him if he knows about an orchard down the highway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He says he does. He bought cider there in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She smiles proudly. She tells him it’s her family’s orchard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They talk about the orchard, then the valley, and how each came to live there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He says he feels lonely living there. He realizes that was inconsiderate to say. But she understands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They talk into the night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He stretches himself across the front bench, brushing against her thighs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She’s surprisingly solid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He hesitates, then opens his sleeping bag invitingly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s cold.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She smiles, but shakes her head. She says she doesn’t get cold anymore. Not in that way. She doesn’t even have any body heat to offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She slithers into the sleeping bag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He feels her press against him. She&#39;s not warm. But not warm is different than cold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They look at each other. His breathing becomes shallow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He removes his gloves. She furrows her brow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s cold.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, his hands gently brush against hers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She intertwines their fingers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He doesn’t feel as cold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holding onto her, he falls asleep. He doesn’t know if she can sleep. He hopes she can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning he wakes to a tapping on his window.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He looks around the cabin. She&#39;s gone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s cold.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Name five things you can see</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/name-five-things-you-can-see/" />
    <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/name-five-things-you-can-see/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Couch. Mirror. Bookcase. Coffee. Dress.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Said aloud when anxious, as instructed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sighed and closed his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then he felt her climb on him. Heard her tell him it was all okay. Smelled her conditioner. Tasted the lingering coffee in her mouth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She led him to the mirror. &amp;quot;Do you see me?&amp;quot; Their eyes met in the reflection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You&#39;re not a thi…”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She held him tighter still.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sighed. &amp;quot;I see you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;And who else do you see?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I see myself.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;And do you see us?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Of course.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The three best things. I think we can work with that.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A milkshake to remember</title>
    <link href="https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/a-milkshake-to-remember/" />
    <updated>2023-06-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://lukegalbraithrussell.github.io/stories/a-milkshake-to-remember/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;His house feels empty, but it isn’t any emptier than it always is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ice cream, milk, mint. Blend. Pour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sighs. He accidentally doubled the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The comforting mint hits his tongue. His shoulders relax.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another sip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A pause.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He remembers he hates mint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Memory erasure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He’d have made them promise not to use that app on him. The memories were of them, but they were his.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet he feels the comfort of someone he doesn’t remember with every sip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each is proof to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He drinks it all hoping to remember.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only the dregs remain.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>